<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Rosemead High School</title>
            <author>Kathryn Loutzenheiser</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>While living in the San Gabriel Valley all of my cousins attended Rosemead High School. The demographics of the school reflect those of the city’s with a 49% Latina/o population and a 47% Asian population (Great Schools). My cousin, being Mexican and Chinese, does not perfectly fit the expectations that can come with being Asian or Latina/o. The chapter, “The Asian and Latino Thing in Schools” discusses the “achievement gap” between Asian and Latina/o students at Alhambra High School and the “model minority myth” which creates inherent racialized expectations for the achievement of Asian-Americans (Cheng 71). These issues at Alhambra are paralleled at Rosemead with similar disparities between Latina/o and Asian-American students with test scores and college readiness (Great Schools). These disparities are part of larger social structures and histories surrounding discrimination against Asians and Latinas/os and the history of suburbanization inequalities in Rosemead.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Kathryn Loutzenheiser">TITLE/PLACENAME</placeName>
            <geo>-118.0712034 34.0841647</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>Rosemead High School is a site for the growth of the youth of Rosemead but is not wholly separated from the histories of racial inequalities of the area.</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Great Schools. Web. 23 February 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl>Cheng, Wendy. The Changs Next Door to the Diazes: Remapping Race in Suburban California. Minnesota Press, 2013.</bibl>
              
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="boxlink.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Kathryn Loutzenheiser, 20 February 2016, Courtesy of Kathryn Loutzenheiser</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
