<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lockheed Plant</title>
            <author>Mario Rodriguez</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>The Lockheed Airport Corporation represented a new industrial wartime economy in the San Fernando Valley. In 1934 Robert E. Gross relocated the company to Union Airport. The Lockheed Plant based in Burbank was an important employer to many throughout the Valley. In particular, some Mexican American families worked in many of the wartime industries that were developed along the railroad corridor cities like Burbank, Pacoima, and San Fernando. Specifically, an oral history of San Fernando native Della Ortega narrated the importance of the Lockheed factory job to her social mobility and economic freedom following tumultuous times in the prior to the war. She worked as a dispatcher for the company and acquired enough income to purchase her own car. Other Mexican American workers participated in similar wartime industries to metigate the labor gap due to the World War II.Today the old Lockheed Plant is located at the presentday Burbank Empire Shopping Center.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Mario Rodriguez">Lockheed Plant</placeName>
            <geo>-118.35323270000004 34.1953614</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>Wartime industries such as the Lockheed Plant represented new economies that local San Fernando Chicano/as could participate in.</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Ortega, Della., and Ramona Frias. Interview by Amy Kitchner. Shades of LA. Shades of LA Interview Project, 1993. Web. 27 September. 1993.</bibl>
               <bibl>Barraclough. “South Central Farmers and Shadow Hills Homeowners: Land Use Policy and Relational Racialization in Los Angeles”. The Professional Geographer 16.2 (2009): 164-186. Print.</bibl>
               <bibl>Citation 3...</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="http://jpg1.lapl.org/00099/00099044.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Schultheis Herman, 1938 Courtesy of LA Public Library, http://jpg1.lapl.org/00099/00099044.jpg </note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
