<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Exide Recycling Plant</title>
            <author>Gabriel Chan</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>Exide Technologies’ battery recycling plant in Vernon began shutting down in March 2015. A government investigation of the nearly twenty years of illegal lead and arsenic dumping at Exide led to their eventual mandatory shut down. The facility had been operating since 1922 and Exide received multiple environmental violations from government officials since 2000. Tests show that toxins are abundant in nearby soil and ground water, and these pollutants have endangered the health of up to 110,000 people. In the mid-1900s, the area was industrial and had a low resident population, so fewer people were at risk. However, the in migration of Latinos beginning in the 1970s caused a demographic shift. The pollutants and dumping now were affecting many more people in the same area. This case is an example of the Vernon’s industrial past conflicting with the present-day high population density of nearby cities, like Huntington Park.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Gabriel Chan">Huntington Park</placeName>
            <geo>-118.192681 34.008279</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>After decades of polluting the surrounding area, Exide Technologies’ battery recycling plant in Vernon is shutting down. The cleanup is ongoing.</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Mason, Melanie. "L.A.-area and State Officials Call for Quicker Cleanup of Exide Plant Contamination." Los Angeles Times. Los Angeles Times, 26 Jan. 2016. Web. 24 Feb. 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl>Barboza, Tony. "Gov. Jerry Brown Wants State to Put $176 Million toward Exide Cleanup." Los Angeles Times. Los Angeles Times, 17 Feb. 2016. Web. 24 Feb. 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl>Barboza, Tony, and Ruben Vives. "Regulators Detail Exide Battery Plant Closure after Decades of Pollution." Los Angeles Times. Los Angeles Times, 12 Mar. 2016. Web. 24 Feb. 2016.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="boxlink.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">CREATOR, DATE. IMAGE COURTESY OF . . . </note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
