<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Santa Ana High School</title>
            <author>Jorge E. Quiroz Moreno</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>Santa Ana High School was established in 1889, making the school 127 years old, and their school mascot is the Saints. The High School's original name was Santa Ana Polytechnic High School, which was located on North Main Street. In 1913, the new site was completed. The school is located at 520 W. Walnut Avenue Santa Ana, Ca 92701. On March 10, 1933, a massive magnitude earthquake hit Southern California, extensively damaging Long Beach and causing serious damage to Santa Ana High School, where the original buildings were demolished in order to make room for the construction of a new high school The school colors are red and white. There are 2,907 student of which 98.5 percent are Hispanic. Their graduation rate in 2013 was 85.0 percent. The School’s Math Proficiency is 39.0 percent and their School Reading/Language Arts Proficiency is 38.0 percent. On May 20, 2015, University of California President Janet Napolitano visited Santa Ana High School aiming to motivate seniors transferring to UC Campuses.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Jorge E. Quiroz Moreno">Santa Ana High School</placeName>
            <geo>-117.87474170000002 33.7436797</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>Santa Ana High School is an institution of education, vital to the city, historically represented, and serves a community of color.</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>"Santa Ana High School." Santa Ana High School. Web. 22 Feb. 2016. http://www.sausd.us/sahs.</bibl>
               <bibl>"Santa Ana High in Santa Ana, California." Santa Ana High in Santa Ana, California. Web. 22 Feb. 2016. http://public-schools.startclass.com/l/13816/Santa-Ana-High.</bibl>
               <bibl>"Orange County Historical Society: History Articles, Santa Ana Polytechnic High School." Orange County Historical Society: History Articles, Santa Ana Polytechnic High School. Web. 22 Feb. 2016. http://www.orangecountyhistory.org/history/richardson-polytechnic.html.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="http://gdurl.com/UqOH"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Jorge Quiroz, 15 February 2016, Courtest of Jorge Quiroz.</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
