<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sylmar Cascades</title>
            <author>Mario Rodriguez</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>The construction of the LA Aqueduct in 1913 marked the transition of San Fernando and the surrounding cities into citrus suburbs. These Citrusburbs or “Agroburbs” were characterized as  semi rural areas that utilized the technological innovations of the aqueduct and railroads to build an agricultural economy. Anglo settlers attempted to impose an idealized utopian agricultural settlement. Garcia states, “...agricultural settlement was universally recognized as the line separating civilization from savagery”(21). Previous settlement of Mexican people was focused on ranching economy. However, new settlement sought to impose a garden citrus utopia that was popular imagery for Southern California boosters. This new settlement produced profitable citrus industries that required Mexican American and immigrant labor to operate. As Garcia remarks, “labor transformed the ‘landscape’ both physically and culturally– of a region…”(19). This transformation was a major impact on Mexican community living conditions and redefined their social status in the San Fernando Valley.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Mario Rodriguez">Sylmar Cascades</placeName>
            <geo>-118.49645051904906 34.321887329222456</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>Technological innovation of LA aqueduct and railroad systems facilitated new suburban developments based on citrus economy in San Fernando.</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Wanamaker, Marc. San Fernando Valley. Charleston, SC: Arcadia Pub., 2011. Print.</bibl>
               <bibl>García, Matt. A World of Its Own: Race, Labor, and Citrus in the Making of Greater Los Angeles, 1900-1970. Chapel Hill, NC: U of North Carolina, 2001. Print.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="http://jpg1.lapl.org/00077/00077896.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Courtesy of LA Public Library, http://jpg1.lapl.org/00077/00077896.jpg</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
