<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sunkist Citrus Packing House</title>
            <author>Kathya Rodriguez</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>The image shows workers in a citrus packing house, better known as Sunkist, in Ontario. The citrus industry became a crucial part of Ontario’s development.. It not only allured new settlers due to the wealth citrus yards brought to its growers, it also provided job opportunities for those who did not have the resources to own land. Low income settlers or long term inhabitant, often of Mexican descent, found jobs either in the citrus field or in the packing houses. The citrus industry also played a key role in segregating people based on race, which is still reflected in settling patterns up to the present day. Although the Sunkist packing house closed in 2008 and Ontario does not rely on citrus as its main product, it still provides most of its residents with industrial and manufacturing jobs. 
</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Kathya Rodriguez">Sunkist Citrus Packing House</placeName>
            <geo>-117.64258 34.056848</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>The citrus industry allured new settlers due to its prosperity and also provided jobs for those who did not own land</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>García, Matt. "The Ideal Country Life: The Development of Citrus Suburbs in Southern California." A World of Its Own: Race, Labor, and Citrus in the Making of Greater Los Angeles, 1900-1970. Chapel Hill, NC: U of North Carolina, 2001. N. pag. Print.</bibl>
               <bibl>Interior of citrus packing house. Ontario. [ca. 1905]. Photograph. University of Southers California. Libraries. USC Digital Library.21 Feb 2016. <http://digitallibrary.usc.edu/cdm/ref/collection/p15799coll65/id/9495>.</bibl>
               <bibl>U.S. Census Bureau: American FactFinder, 2012 Economic Census, 2012 Economic Census of Island Areas, and 2012 Nonemployer Statistics. <http://factfinder.census.gov/faces/nav/jsf/pages/index.xhtml>. (25 Jan 2016).</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="boxlink.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">1905, Image Courtesy of University of Southern California. Libraries, http://digitallibrary.usc.edu/cdm/ref/collection/p15799coll65/id/9495</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
