<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Empty Lot</title>
            <author>Alberto Loaiza</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>An empty lot still sits undeveloped at the edge of Lynwood bordering the city of Watts to this day. It is an indicator of how the city of Lynwood still keeps their distance from its neighboring city notoriously known for their riots of 1965. The city was a spatial concentration of poverty, political isolation, and redlining for a high population of Blacks in Los Angeles. Mayor of Lynwood for thirty years George Higgins states in an interview with the LA Times, “in the ‘40s and ‘50s, if you were black and were caught here after sundown, you had a problem”, the city was considered a Lily White Zone meaning it was dangerous for people of color to even be there. Despite the radical change in Lynwood’s demographics Alameda St remains a racial apartheid and the empty lot a sign that there’s yet no plan to bridge the two neighborhoods.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Alberto Loaiza">Empty Lot</placeName>
            <geo>-118.22065830230713 33.929847862778466</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>The empty lot that sits at the edge of Lynwood and at border of Watts is a sign that Alameda is a border with no plans to encourage development of the area.</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Jack Leonard 29, January. "A City Divided." Los Angeles Times. Los Angeles Times, 29 Jan. 1999. Web. 27 Jan. 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl>Diaz, David R. Barrio Urbanism: Chicanos, Planning, and American Cities. New York: Routledge, 2005. Print.</bibl>
               <bibl>Citation 3...</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="http://s21.postimg.org/snj4fq0nr/IMG_4428.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Alberto Loaiza, 2/24/16, Courtesy of Alberto Loaiza</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
