<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Self-Help Graphics and Art</title>
            <author>Bernice Andrade</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>Self-Help Graphics is a non-profit arts center that was established in 1973. During this time the Chicano Movement was still very active which is why some of its principles are reflected within this community-based center. For instance, Self Help Graphics emphasizes the need to be more inclusive of groups across generational and race differences. It promotes a social consciousness of the Latino community by producing art reflective of peoples’ own experiences and realities. Essentially, it works toward achieving a more open space where communal relationships may develop. By way of fine art printmaking and visual art forms, Self Help Graphics is able to encourage and empower Chicano and Latino artists to showcase their unique talents and artistic abilities. At the same time it serves as an asset to the younger and emerging artists by regularly offering exhibits, classes, and workshops.  </p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Bernice Andrade">“Bernice Andrade” Self-Help Graphics and Art</placeName>
            <geo>-118.22651300000001 34.047363</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>Self-Help Graphics is a community-based arts center that empowers Chicanos and Latinos to showcase their culturally rich artistic abilities. </p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Pulido, Laura, Laura Barraclough, and Wendy Cheng. A People's Guide to Los Angeles. Los 
Angeles: University of California Press, 2012. Print.
</bibl>
               <bibl>Rosenberg, Jeremy. “Culture Power: The Importance of Sister Karen Boccalero & Self Help 
Graphics & Art in Los Angeles History.” LA History Archive. Studio for Southern California History, n. d. Web. 20 Feb. 2016.  http://lahistoryarchive.socalstudio.org/resources/Boccalero/essay.html
</bibl>
               <bibl>Self Help Graphics & Art: Art Transforms Communities. Self Help Graphics & Art, 2015. Web. 
20 Feb. 2016. http://selfhelpgraphics.com/
</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="boxlink.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Courtesy of Remezcla, http://remezcla.com/culture/self-help-graphics-arts-dia-de-los-muertos-promo-video/</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
