<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Santa Ana Regional Transportation Center</title>
            <author>Kevin Martinez</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>Santa Ana Regional Transportation Center is a passenger rail station and transportation center that serves commuters in the region. Amtrak’s Pacific Surfliner, Metrolink’s Orange County Line and Inland Empire-Orange County Line trains utilize the tracks as part of their daily routes. The station was designed in a Spanish Colonial Revival style that complements much of the region’s buildings from the earlier Spanish era (Great American Stations).The external walls have a stucco finish, the roofs are laid in red Spanish tile, and a light brown stone is used for the trim. In all, the building’s façade retains a mission appearance. Spanish and Mission Revival architecture became quite popular in southern California in the late 19th century. Los Angeles boosters promoted the revitalization movement as a way to connect to the state’s Spanish past, which was romanticized in order to attract settlers from other parts of the country to relocate and to create a regional character (Deverell 142).</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Kevin Martinez">The Train Station</placeName>
            <geo>-117.85551 33.75160</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>The train station with a Spanish Colonial style is a central transportation hub that commuters utilize on daily bases. </p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Deverell, William. Whitewashed Adobe: The Rise of Los Angeles and the Remaking of Its Mexican Past. 1st ed. University of California Press, 2004. Web</bibl>
               <bibl>"Great American Stations." Santa Ana, CA -. Web. 24 Feb. 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl>Citation 3...</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="boxlink.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Kevin Martinez, 8 Ferbuary 2016, Courtesy of Kevin Martinez</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
