<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Rosemead Public Library</title>
            <author>Kathryn Loutzenheiser</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>This library is located in a central space with City Hall, the Rosemead Chamber of Commerce, a market plaza and residential spaces on adjacent streets. Inside is a communal Children’s Area with multiple desks. This communal space focused on family interaction is a reflection of Rosemead’s current investment on fostering a diverse city. This is related to the term “contact hypothesis”, defined by Ochoa as “the more frequent the interaction, the less likely the conflict” (Ochoa 127). From a suburb in the 1930s that was exclusively white to a multiethnic majority Asian and Latina/o suburb today, spaces such as a public library contribute to understandings borne from shared space. Visiting on a Saturday afternoon the multiethnic demographics consisted of children, adults and elderly. While exploring the space I came across a manga graphic novel in Spanish which is an interesting window into the mix of cultures situated in Rosemead.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Kathryn Loutzenheiser">"Kathryn Loutzenheiser" Rosemead Public Library</placeName>
            <geo>-118.0770963 34.0801603</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>TEXT SUMMARY</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Ochoa, Gilda L. Becoming Neighbors in a Mexican American Community: Power, Conflict, and Solidarity. University of Texas Press, Austin. 2004.</bibl>
              
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="boxlink.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Kathryn Loutzenheiser, 20 February 2016, Courtesy of Kathryn Loutzenheiser</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
