<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Jurupa Valley Dog Park</title>
            <author>Jose Cardona</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>Jurupa Valley is California's newest city; it is located in the upper western region of Riverside County (Jurupa Valley). The city itself is made up of fragmented neighborhoods, commercial areas, and industrial zones. Poor neighborhoods that began as Mexican immigrant barrios over 150 years ago, when the citrus industry was in full swing, are separated by wealthier, white neighborhoods. (Garcia; Gonzales). The poorer communities of the city known as Rubidoux and Mira Loma are separated by Pedley and the Indian Hills neighborhood (Policy Map). Furthermore, the construction of newer suburbs has added to the disparities within the city. These disparities become physically visible when one pays attention to the fact that the wealthier (and often whiter) neighborhoods have nicer roads, are next to the better high school and have access to the nicer recreational facilities, and are also furthest from the factories, the warehouses, and the logistical centers.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Jose Cardona">Jose Cardona, Jurupa Valley Dog Park</placeName>
            <geo>-117.429 33.987</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>Jurupa Valley is a city with emerging middle class suburban neighborhoods, old barrios and the largest inland port in the country. </p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>“PolicyMappingMexicanMales.” Policymap.com. 2010, 2009. Web. 4 Jan 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl>“City of Jurupa Valley About the City History.” City of Jurupa Valley About The City History. N.p., n.d. Web. 8 Feb. 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl>Garcia, Matt. A World of Its Own: Race, Labor and Citrus in the Making of Greater Los Angeles, 1900-1970. Chapel Hill ; London: U of North-Carolina, 2001. Print.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="http://i.imgur.com/fSKvK5l.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">The City of Jurupa Valley, 8/21/2014, Image Courtesy of The City of Jurupa Valley, http://jurupavalley.org/Portals/21/Images/Pictures/0815.jpg</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
