<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>FELI-MEX MARKET</title>
            <author>Monica Rodas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>Feli-Mex Market is a mini market located on N. Figueroa St. and Ave 54, which sell a variety of produce and is also distant from local supermarkets within Highland Park. However, this mini market is significant because it also depicts the barrio “state of mind” and how these spaces are similar to barrios. Mini markets are essential for barrios that are distant from supermarkets and are secluded from larger commercial places. This mini market has become part of Highland Park’s economy and has brought businesses from old spaces into this Latino suburb. The mini market and other local places also hold strong significance in the Chicano Civil Rights movement, in which these spaces created discussion amongst community members on problems of discrimination and finding solutions for future generations. The role these open spaces have played in moments of struggle shows how the Latino suburb still connect to a past time.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Monica Rodas">FELI-MEX MARKET</placeName>
            <geo>-118.197166 34.108279</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>Feli-Mex Market signifies spaces where the Chicano Movement was openly discussed and the barrio “state of mind” followed Latino suburbs.</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>"Highland Park: Brown and Proud." KCET. Web. 22 Feb. 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl>Diaz, David R. Barrio Urbanism: Chicanos, Planning, and American Cities. New York: Routledge, 2005.</bibl>
               <bibl>Garcia, Matt. "Chapter Two: The 'Colonia Complex' Revisited." A World of Its Own: Race, Labor, and Citrus in the Making of Greater Los Angeles, 1900-1970. University of North Carolina Press, 2001.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="http://i.imgur.com/uMGWImv.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Monica Rodas, 20 February 2016, Courtesy of Monica Rodas</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
