<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Warehouses and Distribution Center</title>
            <author>Jose Cardona</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>The logistics industry is very big in the city of Jurupa Valley. The city houses the largest inland port in the country (Gonzales). It is because of this industry that the city has become one of the most polluted cities in Southern California (LA Times). To better understand this industry within the context of Jurupa Valley we must unpack the greater forces at play in the creation of this enormous inland port. All the warehouses and the distribution centers are located in a part of Jurupa Valley called Mira Loma. Mira Loma is historic barrio of Rancho Jurupa that has evolved into an area that is now over 50% Mexican with a large portion of that population being first or second generation immigrants (Policy Map; Gonzales). As a result, the logistics industry has access to a flexible, cheap, and a racialized labor force (Gonzales). According Alfonso Gonzales's text, "Reform without Justice" this industry was able to settle in Jurupa Valley because of Riverside County's "laissez-faire treatment of the issue." The lack of interest by the county is a common thread found in other environmental injustice cases. Industries that cause a lot of pollution are usually centered near low income, minority communities. Companies know these communities tend to have little education and can be easily taken advantage of. </p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Jose Cardona">Jose Cardona, Warehouses and Distribution Center</placeName>
            <geo>-117.525 34.012</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>The city has the largest inland port in the country, which takes advantage of the large first and second generation immigrant labor force.</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Barboza, Tony. "People Living near 60 Freeway in Ontario Breathe the Worst Air in the Southland." Los Angeles Times. Los Angeles Times, 9 Sept. 2015. Web. 21 Feb. 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl>“PolicyMappingHispanicPopulation.” Policymap.com. 2010, 2009. Web. 20 Feb 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl>Gonzales, Alfonso. "Globalization and Demographic Change in Riverside County." Reform without Justice: Latino Migrant Politics and the Homeland Security State. New York: Oxford UP, 2014. N. pag. Print.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="boxlink.jpg"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Google Maps, 2/21/2016. Image Courtesy of Goole Maps</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
