<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Downtown Santa Ana</title>
            <author>Jorge E. Quiroz Moreno</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher></publisher>
            <date when="2015">Winter 2016</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <relatedItem>
               <bibl>
                  <author></author>
               </bibl>
            </relatedItem>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      
      <body>
         <div type="article"><!-- Enclose each paragraph of your text in a new <p></p> tag. -->
            <p>Downtown Santa Ana is an urban center for Santa Ana that is highlighted by culture. Many locally owned small businesses directly advertise to the Latino consumer on Fourth Street, known in Spanish as “La Cuatro.” In the mid-1980s, Fiesta Marketplace opened catering to a Latino clientele. In the 2000s there was a shift away from the Latino customer. There is entertainment, art, music,and restaurants that have been gentrifying this area and bringing in new business investors catering to young millennial and hipsters. In 2011, Fiesta Marketplace was renamed “East End”. This is highlighted by the Artwalk filled with galleries down Broadway, Proof Bar, Yost Theatre, and in 2015 4th Street Market. Fourth Street is home to The Ronald Reagan Federal Building and U.S. Courthouse, Southern Division. La Libreria Martinez on Broadway opened its doors in 1993 catering to the Latino communities' need for a bookshop. In 2012, it became La Libreria Martinez de Chapman University and in 2016 Chapman University’s College of Educational Studies (CES), or Centro Comunitario de Educación. The Old Courthouse on Santa Ana Blvd is a historical landmark built in 1901, Southern California’s oldest court building. It now serves as a free museum.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      
      <back>
         
         <note type="mapmarker"><!-- this will be the title & text in your map marker pop-up -->
            <placeName type="Jorge E. Quiroz Moreno">Downtown Santa Ana</placeName>
            <geo>-117.86968856007996 33.74800461491911</geo><!-- geocoordinates here. !! enter in the lattitude first, then the longitude !! you can look up coordinates here: http://www.gps-coordinates.net -->
            <p>Downtown Santa Ana is the city's cultural center of art, entertainment, music, eateries, and Orange County's historical center of governance.</p>
         </note>
         
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gonzalez, Ron. "Libreria Martinez Becomes Part of Chapman University Educational Initiative." The Orange County Register. 18 Sept. 2012. Web. 22 Feb. 2016. http://www.ocregister.com/articles/martinez-371900-chapman-santa.html.</bibl>
               <bibl>"Old Orange County Courthouse." Orange County, California. Web. 22 Feb. 2016.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
         <div type="images">
            <figure xml:id="fig1">
               <graphic url="http://gdurl.com/R565"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Jorge Quiroz, 15 February 2016, Courtest of Jorge Quiroz</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            <figure xml:id="fig2">
               <graphic url="http://gdurl.com/wa20"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Jorge Quiroz, 15 Ferbruary 2016, Courtest of Jorge Quiroz</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
            <figure xml:id="fig3">
               <graphic url="http://gdurl.com/nu68"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Jorge Quiroz, 15 Ferbruary 2016, Courtest of Jorge Quiroz</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
             <figure xml:id="fig4">
               <graphic url="http://gdurl.com/7Bd5"/>
               <head></head>
               <note type="attribution">Jorge Quiroz, 15 Ferbruary 2016, Courtest of Jorge Quiroz</note>
               <figDesc></figDesc>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
